Guide to the William Blathwayt Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1646-1796; Series I; 4.0' (10 boxes)
  - Blathwayt, William, 1649?-1717
    - AL (draft) to Robert Yard, 1698 Aug 8/18 (Box 2, Folder 44)
      Writing in this and succeeding letters to Yard, the secretary of the Lords Justices; the Commissioners nominated to suppress piracy in the East Indies should proceed on their business. 1. Yard, Robert. 2. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 3. Pirates.
    - L (draft) to Robert Yard, Loo, 1698 Aug 11/21
      Wanting the Lords Justices to consider the Merchants' petition. 1. Yard, Robert. 2. Great Britain. Lords Justices.
    - L (draft) to Robert Yard, 1698 Aug 15/25 (Box 2, Folder 44a)
      Concerning the victualling bill in Spain and the commission to suppress piracy in the East Indies. 1. Yard, Robert. 2. Great Britain. Commissioners for Victualling. 3. Pirates.
    - AL (draft) to Robert Yard, 1698 Aug 19/29
      Concerning the regiments to be sent to Jersey and Guernsey. 1. Yard, Robert. 2. Great Britain. Army.
    - L (draft) to Robert Yard, 1698 Sep 2
      Conveying orders for the East Indies squadron; accompanied by a page of holograph instructions for the regiments bound for the West Indies. 1. Yard, Robert. 2. Great Britain. Navy.
    - L (draft) to Robert Yard, Loo, 1698 Sep 5
      Directions for Mr. Aylmer to demand satisfaction from the Republic of Genoa for the injuries outlined in Blackwell's memorial. 1. Yard, Robert. 2. Aylmer, Matthew Aylmer, Baron, d. 1720. 3. Blackwell, Lambert, Sir, d. 1727. 4. Great Britain--Foreign relations--Genoa.
    - L (draft) to [Robert Yard?], Loo, 1698 Sep 5/15
      Discussion of the role of the marine regiments in the West Indies; Aylmer's squadron; East Indies pirates. 1. Yard, Robert. 2. Great Britain. Navy. 3. Great Britain--Colonies --West Indies. 4. Pirates.
    - L (draft) to Robert Yard, Loo, 1698 Sep 15/25
      Concerning the pardon to be offered to pirates in the East Indies who surrender themselves. 1. Yard, Robert. 2. Pirates.
    - L (draft) to Robert Yard, Loo, 1698 Oct 14/24 (Box 2, Folder 44b)
      The king gives permission for the new ambassador to the Great Mogul to travel on an East India Company ship and empowers the Lords Justices to approve of Norris if he should be nominated by the company. 1. Yard, Robert. 2. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 3. East India Company (English) 4. Norris, William, 1st Baronet, 1657-1702.
    - L (draft) to Robert Yard, Loo, 1698 Oct 25/
      - West Indies squadron; the king wishes, Nov 4
      - to know the opinion of the Lords Justices about a proper time for the meeting of Parliament. 1. Yard, Robert. 2. Great Britain. Navy. 3. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 4. Great Britain. Parliament, 1698.
    - L (draft) to Robert Yard, Loo, 1698 Oct 28/
      - The king intends to return a, Nov 7
      - fortnight before the meeting of Parliament. 1. Yard, Robert. 2. Great Britain. Parliament, 1698.
    - AL (draft) to Robert Yard, 1698 Dec 9
      Sir Henry Furnese has begun to solicit for the return of the silver seized in Rotterdam from an East India Company ship. Accompanied by a holograph draft to James Vernon of the same date and similar content. 1. Yard, Robert. 2. Furnese, Henry, 1st Baronet, 1658?-1712. 3. East India Company (English). 4. Vernon, James, 1646-1727.
    - L (draft) to Robert Yard, Loo, 1699 Jul 14/24
      Concerning payment by the Hudson Bay Company for goods seized from the French at Fort York; naval matters. 1. Yard, Robert. 2. Hudson's Bay Company. 3. Great Britain. Navy. 4. Great Britain--Foreign relations --France.
    - 2 AL (drafts) to Robert Yard, 1700 Oct 18
      - Acknowledges receipt of a letter., Oct. 11/22
      - Mentions troop movements around Rotterdam; the prorogation of Parliament; mentions two letters concerning the island of Santa Lucia. 1. Yard, Robert. 2. Great Britain. Army. 3. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 4. Great Britain. Parliament. 5. Rooke, George, Sir, 1650-1709.
    - AL (draft, in French) to unidentified recipient, London, 1698 May 10/20 (Box 2, Folder 45)
      Concerning the climate and politics in the American colonies. 1. Great Britain--Colonies--America.
    - AL (draft) to an unnamed recipient, 1716 Aug 25
      Concerning his petition relating to a fine for the renewal of the grant for his house.
    - Unidentified, 1716 Aug 25
      The writer seems to have been head of an Oxford college. Returns a receipt for an appointment which was given him "Midsummer last." 1. Davenant, James, Dean of Oriel, ca. 1650-1720. 2. Pelling, John, 1670-1750.
    - Miscellaneous, 1708 Dec 31
      Receipt for 626 gilders which were given to Isabella Paarden and which were guaranteed by Blathwayt.
  - Bolton, Charles Powlett, 2nd Duke of, 1661-1722
    - Letter (copy) to [the Lords Justices?], Dublin Castle, 1698 Nov 19 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      Report from the Lords Justices of Ireland about proceedings in the Irish Parliament, including a breach of privilege against the Bishop of Derry; signed by Winchester and Galway. I. Ruvigny and Raineval, Henri de Massue de Ruvigny, 2nd Marquis of, 1648-1720. II. Ireland. Lords Justices and Council. 1. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 2. Ireland. Parliament, 1698. 3. King, William, Archbishop of Dublin, 1650-1729.
  - Boselli, Galeazzo, Conte
    - ALS (in Italian) to William III, Bastille, 1701 Mar 12
      - Assuring the king of his innocence and enclosing a memorial. 1. William III, King of Great Britain, 1650-1702.
        See: Oversize, Box 12, folder 233.
  - Bowles, Phineas, d. 1722
    - ALS to [William Blathwayt?], Torbay, 1693 Aug 20
      Writing in his capacity as secretary to the Admiralty about movements of the fleet, supplies, etc. 1. Great Britain. Admiralty. 2. Great Britain. Navy.
  - Bridgewater, John Egerton, 3rd Earl of, 1646-1701
    - 2 ALS to [William Blathwayt], London, 1699 Jul 11
      - Reporting the replacement of Edmond, Aug 1
      - Dummer with David Furzer as Surveyor of the Navy, and giving news of the illness of Sir Robert Rich and the Duke of Leeds. 1. Dummer, Edmond. 2. Furzer, David, d. 1715. 3. Leeds, Thomas Osborne, Duke of, 1631-1712. 4. Rich, Robert, 2nd baronet, 1648-1699.
    - 3 ALS to [William Blathwayt], London, 1700 Jul 16-
      - Expressing pleasure at the king's, Sep 17
      - good health and dismay at the Duke of Gloucester's death; other news. 1. William III, King of Great Britain, 1650-1702. 2. William, Duke of Gloucester, 1689-1700.
  - Brill, Hend[rik]
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Amsterdam, 1682/3 Feb 3 (Box 2, Folder 47)
      Report from the Consul of Amsterdam about the death of Lord Shaftesbury. 1. Shaftesbury, Anthony Ashley Cooper, 1st Earl of, 1621-1683.
  - Brograve, Henry
    - ALS to [William Blathwayt], Antigua, 1685 Jul 25
      Sending Blathwayt his 1/2 percent of goods. 1. Great Britain--Colonies--Leeward Islands.
  - Broughton, Hugh
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Venice, 1695 Apr 8 (Box 2, Folder 48)
      Writing as English consul in Venice about Venetian affairs, and putting forth his case for arrears in pay. 1. Great Britain--Foreign relations --Venice.
    - Newsletter, Venice, 1697 Oct 10
      Describing his dinner with the English Merchants. 1. Newsletters.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Venice, 1699 Jun 26
      Concerning his role as consul in Venice, accompanied by a copy of his Newsletter to Secretary Vernon. 1. Newsletters.
  - Burchett, Josiah
    - 5 letters, copies, to Robert Yard, 1698 Sep 16-
      - Copies of communications between the, Nov 12
      - Admiralty and Lords Justices sent by Yard to Blathwayt. 1. Yard, Robert. 2. Great Britain. Admiralty. 3. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 4. Schovell, Clowdisley, Sir, 1650-1707. 5. Great Britain. Navy.
  - Burghley, William Cecil, Baron, 1520-1598
    - Letter, 1575 Sep 15 (copy) to Lord Cobham, Theobalds, n.d.
      Concerning the plans for a French marriage for Queen Elizabeth. The copy was apparently made in the 17th century for use by a printer. 1. Cobham, Henry Brooke, 8th Baron, 1564-1619. 2. Elizabeth I, Queen of England, 1533-1603.
  - Burrow, John
    - 2 LS to William Blathwayt, Livorno, 1697/8 Jan 13 (Box 2, Folder 49)
      - Writing as English Consul in Leghorn, 1699 Aug 14
      - with the news and gratitude to Blathwayt for his support in procuring him the consulate in Marseilles. Accompanied by copy of Burrow's affidavit, 1698 May 29, refuting charges, attested by Sir Lambert Blackwell. 1. Blackwell, Lambert, Sir, d. 1727.
  - Butts, John
    - 20 ALS to William Blathwayt, Helsingör and Copenhagen, 1692/3 Feb 10-
      - Butts was English Consul at Helsingör, 1693 Sep 5
      - with responsibility for reporting ship movements and convoys in the Sound and Ports of Denmark. He mentions the movements of the Jacobite peer Balcarres in his letter of Jul 15 and notes the arrival of Lexington as Envoy on Aug 12. 1. Great Britain--Foreign relations --Denmark. 2. Lexington, Robert Sutton, 2nd Baron, 1661-1723. 3. Balcarres, Colin Lindsay, 3rd Earl of, 1654?-1722.
  - Byrd, William
    - Memorandum of the balance due at Byrd's death on his account of quit rents of Virginia, n.p., 1707 Aug 18
      With an account also of the present Receiver General's (Brydison) quit rents due. This document is badly damaged and the sums have been lost, but cf. Collection of Treasury Books XXI, pt. pp. 200-03. 1. Byrd, William, 1674-1744. 2. Virginia--History--Colonial period, ca. 1600-1775.
  - Capel, Henry Capel, Baron, d. 1696
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Dublin Castle, 1694 Dec 26 (Box 3, Folder 50)
      Recommending that one Goffton be given a commission in the Army of Ireland. 1. Great Britain. Army.
  - Cardonnel, Adam, d. 1719
    - ALS to William Lowndes, Camp at Hays, 170[3] Jun 4
      Reporting Marlborough's approval of payment to Captain Porter. Accompanied by a memorial of "allowances craved by Captain Porter & proposed by the Report" and by two copies of "the case of Capt[ai]n Porter." 1. Lowndes, William, 1652-1724. 2. Great Britain. Treasury. I. Marlborough, John Churchill, 1st Duke of, 1650-1722. II. Porter, John.
    - AL to [William Blathwayt], n.p., [1702 Oct 9]
      Reporting Marlborough's response to directions about mustering several regiments. 1. Marlborough, John Churchill, 1st Duke of, 1650-1722.
  - Carlingford, Francis Taaffe, 3rd Earl of, 1639-1704
    - ALS (in French) to [William Blathwayt], Vienna, 1697 Dec 10 (Box 3, Folder 51)
      Writing about his Irish lands.
    - ALS (in French) to unidentified recipient, Luneville, 1698 Jun 28
      Writing to an English peer on behalf of the Duke of Lorraine about the latter's marriage and loyalty to England. 1. Leopold, Duke of Lorraine, 1679-1729.
  - Carlisle, Charles Howard, 3rd Earl of, 1669-1738
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Naworth, 1693/4 Feb 19
      Reporting on military matters in Carlisle. 1. Great Britain. Army.
  - Carlisle, England. Inhabitants
    - Letter, signed to the Earl of Essex, Carlisle, 1702 Nov 26
      About expanding the area of the quarters for a troop of dragoons. Signed by the recorder, mayor, and eight other citizens. 1. Essex, Algernon Capell, 2nd Earl of, 1670-1758. 2. Great Britain. Army.
  - Castleton, George Saunderson, 5th Viscount, 1631-1714
    - 2 ALS to William Blathwayt, n.p., 1694 May 15 (Box 3, Folder 52)
      - Asking Blathwayt to help use his, Oct 5
      - influence to get his son a Mayor's commission and later a position with Lord Lexington during his negotiations. 1. Castleton, James Saunderson, Earl, d. 1723. 2. Lexington, Robert Sutton, 2nd Baron, 1661-1723.
  - Catholic Church
    - List of controversial works: anonymous manuscript, ca. 1670
      Apparently a list of proscribed and controversial works, with page references and call numbers in the Biblioteca Guelter [?] 1. Index Librorum Prohibitorum. 2. Catholic Church--Doctrinal and controversial works. 3. Libraries --History.
    - "Ecclesiastical Interdict": contemporary manuscript copy, in Latin, 1687 Dec 26
      Against the parish church of St. Louis, in France, for admitting an excommunicated person to Communion. Accompanied by an English copy.
  - Catinat de la Fauconnerie, Nicolas de, 1637-1712
    - "Estat de l'Infanterie que M. de Cattinat à soûbs ses Ordres": contemporary manuscript (copy), [1695?] (Box 3, Folder 53)
      The list of French troops was prepared for the use of Lord Galway. 1. France. Army. 2. Ruvigny and Raineval, Henri de Massue de Ruvigny, 2nd Marquis of, 1648-1720. Grand Alliance, War of the, 1689- 1697.
  - Charles XII, King of Sweden
    - LS to William III (in German), 1697 Jun 23
      Following his father's example, the King of Sweden promises to maintain friendly ties with England so long as England continues to extend the same friendly consideration to Sweden. 1. Great Britain--Foreign relations --Sweden.
  - Chester, England
    - "Present State of the Stores at Chester," Chester, 1688/9 Feb 1
      - Inventory of all provisions in Chester Castle under the charge of Peter Shakerley. Accompanied by "A State of Amunition & Armes at Carlisle & Chester." 1. Great Britain. Army. 2. Carlisle, England. 3. Shakerley, Peter.
        See: Oversize, Box 12, folder 234
  - Church of England
    - "Some Heads of things to be more fully insisted upon by the Bishops in their Addresses to the Clergy and People": contemporary manuscript copy, [1687] (Box 3, Folder 54)
      Outline of program to strengthen the established Church against the "Popish Emissarys" while maintaining obedience to the monarch. 1. Catholic Church--England.
    - A Defence of the Established Church and the Penal Laws: anonymous manuscript, [ca. 1687]
      Arguing that the Catholics and Dissenters have earned their treatment through their seditious activities and intolerant behavior. 1. Catholic Church--England. 2. Dissenters.
  - Clarendon, Henry Hyde, 2nd Earl of, 1638-1709
    - "The Lord Clarendon's Speech at the Resignment of the Sword": contemporary manuscript copy, [1687 Feb]
      Addressed to the Lords Justices of Ireland at his replacement as viceroy by Tyrconnel, whose comments are also recorded. 1. Ireland, Lords Justices and council. I. Tyrconnel, Richard Talbot, Earl of, 1630-1691.
  - Clarke, George, 1661-1736
    - 9 ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1696 May 22- (Box 3, Folder 55)
      - Reporting on military matters--troop, Sep 8
      - movements, payment of soldiers, problems of discipline, Lieutenant Medlicott's case, etc. 1. Great Britain. Army.
    - 13 ALS and 1 LS to William Blathwayt, 1698 Jul 26-
      - Reporting on military matters, Nov 4
      - --reduction in troops and complaints by officers, subsistence rates, quartering of troops, orders by Lords Justices, chaplains, troop movements, and the sailing of Collingwood's regiment for the West Indies. 1. Great Britain. Army. 2. Great Britain. Lords Justices. 3. Great Britain--Colonies--West Indies.
    - LS to William Blathwayt, Admiralty Office, 1702 Dec 21
      Conveying, by direction of the Prince, the Queen's orders for putting nine companies of Marines on board ships bound for Portugal. 1. George, Prince of Denmark, 1653-1708. 2. Great Britain. Navy.
    - LS to William Blathwayt, Admiralty Office, 1702[3] Jan 29
      Concerning orders for Marines "to goe aboard the Fleete." 1. Great Britain. Navy. 2. George, Prince of Denmark, 1653-1708.
  - Cockett, Peter
    - Letter (copy) to the Lords of the Admiralty, n.p., 1693 Sep 24 (Box 3, Folder 56)
      Cockett was an English privateer and in this letter he reports on an unsuccessful attempt against eleven French merchant ships. Another copy is described in C.S.P.D., 1693, p. 339. 1. Great Britain. Admiralty.
  - Codrington, Christopher, d. 1698
    - Letter (copy) to [William Blathwayt], Antigua, 1698 Jun 10
      Writing as governor of the Leeward Islands in acknowledgment of royal orders to return the island of St. Christopher to the French, and raising the question of three other small islands captured from the French. 1. Great Britain--Colonies--Leeward Islands.
  - Colenbine, Ventris
    - 2 ALS and 2 LS to William Blathwayt, Portsmouth, 1702/3 Jan 28-
      - Reporting the depletion in his, Feb 13
      - regiment through death and desertion and the refusal of some French dragoons to join him as foot soldiers. Accompanied by a memorandum, signed on the number of men needed to complete his regiment. 1. Great Britain. Army.
  - Colt, William Dutton, Sir, d. 1693
    - Memorial (in German) relating to his mission to the Landgrave of Hesse-Cassel: anonymous manuscript, [ca. 1689] (Box 3, Folder 57)
      A 57-point report describing a conference. 1. Great Britain--Foreign relations --Hesse-Cassel.
  - "Conference at Vienna"
    - Account (in French) of a meeting concerning the alliance against France., 1695 Feb 8
  - Coningsby, Thomas Coningsby, Earl, 1656?-1729
    - ALS to [William Blathwayt], Dublin, 1698 Oct 1
      Asking Blathwayt to expedite a warrant in his favor from the Treasury. 1. Great Britain. Treasury.
  - Consbruck, C. A.
    - Letter (copy, in French) to Mons. Hop, Du Logis, 1698 Dec 26 (Box 3, Folder 58)
      Concerning the appearance of one Lieutenant Colonel Klinkenström at the Imperial Court. 1. Hop, Jacob. 2. Netherlands-- Foreign relations--Holy Roman Empire.
  - Copsey, Charles
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Portsmouth, 1702 Nov 8
      Asks Blathwayt to provide quarters and assignments for him and his regiment.
  - Cosimo III, de 'Medici, grand duke of Tuscany, 1642-1723
    - ALS (in Italian) to [William III?], Firenze, 1700 [Sep?] 10
      1. William III, King of Great Britain, 1650-1702.
  - Coxe, N.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 59)
      The tutor of Blathwayt's children asks his patron to provide him with a quarterly allowance.
  - Crawford, J.
    - 2 ALS to William Blathwayt, n.p., 1698 Aug 18
      - Writing as commissary of musters on, Sep 16
      - military matters, and recommending Bonithon Steward to be judge on one of the circuits. 1. Great Britain. Army.
    - ALS to Samuel Lynn, Horse Guard, 1702 Sep 17
      Requesting a pass from musters for Washington Shirley. 1. Lynn, Samuel, d. 1737. 2. Great Britain. Army. 3. Ferrers, Washington Shirley, 2nd Earl, 1677-1729.
    - Document (signed): certificate of muster, Whitehall, 1703 Nov 22
      For Captain John Porter's company during 25 April to 24 June 1703. 1. Great Britain. Army.
  - Crawford, R., Colonel
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Sheerness, 1702 May 30 (Box 3, Folder 60)
      Asks for specific instructions for the embarkment of his company.
  - Crew, Nathaniel Crew, 3rd Baron, Bishop of Durham, 1633-1721
    - "Queries put by the Bishop of Durham, to the Clergy of his diocese": contemporary manuscript copy, [1687]
      Concerning their reaction to liberty of conscience and suspension of the penal laws. On the verso are pencilled notes, apparently by Sir Robert Southwell, about the construction of sea walls. 1. Church of England--Clergy. I. Southwell, Robert, Sir, 1635-1702.
  - Dalzell, Robert, 1662-1758
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Portsmouth, 1702/3 Feb 15 (Box 3, Folder 61)
      Reporting that Colonel Gibson went to St. Helen's where Colenbine's regiment is on board four Transport ships. 1. Gibson, John, Sir, 1637-1717. 2. Colenbine, Ventris. 3. Great Britain. Navy.
  - Danckelman, P.
    - Letter (copy, in French) to [William Blathwayt], The Hague, 1701 Oct 22
      Contending that he should share a full role with Stepney in the Aulic council at Vienna. 1. Stepney, George, 1663-1707. 2. Great Britain--Foreign relations --Holy Roman Empire.
  - Dartmouth, George Legge, 1st Baron of, 1648-1691
    - Memorandum, holograph: "Warrants for his Highness the Prince of Orange's signing." n.p., [1688/9 Jan]
      - Two items marked "done" by Blathwayt. 1. William III, King of Great Britain, 1650-1702. 2. Great Britain. Army. 3. Chester, England.
        See: Oversize: Box 12, folder 235
  - Dereham, Thomas, Sir, d. 1697
    - AL to William Blathwayt, Florence, 1683/4 Jan 18 (Box 3, Folder 62)
      Describes the summer dress of Roman citizens. Dereham was envoy to the Court of Tuscany. 1. Rome (City)--Description--To 1800.
  - Dorset, Charles Sackville, 6th Earl of, 1638-1706
    - LS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1694 May 22
      Cover letter for the grant making Sir Fleetwood Sheppard Usher of the Black Rod. 1. Sheppard, Fleetwood, Sir, 1634- 1698.
  - East India Company (English)
    - List of ships arrived at Kinsale, 1703 Oct 3 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Ebeling, Monsieur d'
    - Memorandum on military strategy (in French), [ca. 1695]
      Referring to engagements against the French during the War of the Grand Alliance. 1. Grand Alliance, War of the, 1689-1697.
  - Eberhard IV, Herzog von Württemberg-Stuttgart
    - Letter (in French) to [William Blathwayt], n.p., 1695 Dec 8
      Concerning officers absent from their troops. 1. Grand Alliance, War of the, 1689-1697.
  - Edgworth, Francis, d. 1722
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, n.p., [1702 Dec 18] (Box 3, Folder 64)
      Asking for a regiment in lieu of £730 royal debt to his father, Sir John Edgworth. 1. Edgworth, John, Sir, d. 1702?
  - Edwards, Richard
    - ALS to John Edwards, Cansford, 1737 Feb 14
      Sending a copy of their father's will and an abstract of their mother's jointure.
  - Ellis, John, 1643?-1738
    - 2 ALS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1701 Aug 4
      - Describes the instrument of, Oct 10
      - ratification for the treaty of alliance with Denmark and sends news of associations and libels. 1. Great Britain. Treaties, etc., 1694-1702, (William III).
  - Erle, Thomas, 1650?-1720
    - 5 ALS to William Blathwayt, Portsmouth, Vilvorde, and Bruges, 1695/6 Mar 1-
      - Reporting the situation in Portsmouth, 1696 Oct 2
      - harbor and with the Army in Flanders, and describing his efforts to get the citizens of Portsmouth to sign an Association. 1. Great Britain. Army. 2. Gibson, John, Sir, 1637-1717. 3. Portsmouth, England.
  - Faria, Juan de
    - "Informacion que haze Juan de Faria": contemporary manuscript copy (in Portuguese), [1680] (Box 3, Folder 65)
      See: Oversize, Box 12, folder 236
  - Fitzpatrick, Edward
    - 2 ALS to [William Blathwayt], Gravesend, 1695/6 Mar 10
      - Detailed reports on the arrival of, Mar 12
      - transport ships from Ostende at Gravesend, including two lists of ships with names of regiments, number of men, etc. 1. Great Britain. Army. 2. Great Britain. Navy.
  - Fox, Charles, d. 1713
    - Certificate, signed, [ca. 1698]
      A list of French Reformed officers permitted to return to their regiments in Ireland, with notes of their travel allowance. 1. Great Britain. Army. 2. Great Britain. Army. French Reformed officers.
  - France. Navy
    - List of ships bound for Martinique, 1706 Jun (Box 3, Folder 66)
      List of ten ships with notes on number of men and guns; the ships were spotted by English vessels. 1. Spanish Succession, War of the, 1701-1714. 2. Great Britain. Navy.
    - "List of the French Fleet": contemporary manuscript copy, [1697]
      With notes of the number of men and guns, and accompanied by an abstract of the French Navy.
  - France, Sovereigns, etc., 1643-1715. (Louis XIV)
    - Draft warrant (in French), anonymous manuscript, Fontainebleau, 1697 Oct 13
      Concerning Louis Alexandre, Duc d'Amuille.
  - Frankland, Thomas, Sir, 2nd baronet, 1665?-1726
    - LS to William Blathwayt, General Post Office, 1702 Dec 30
      Concerning the boats used to carry mail between England and Holland. Also signed by R. Cotton. 1. Great Britain. Post Office. I. Cotton, R.
  - Friesen, Julius Heinrich, Graf von
    - 32 ALS (in French) to William Blathwayt, The Hague, Frankfurt, Augsburg, Vienna, Camp at Bruchsal, 1696/7 Jan 2/12- (Box 3, Folder 67)
      - Writing as commander-in-chief of, 1697 Jun 28